

Ong Jia Ying

Phone: +6016-5506865 **Email:** <u>iying1997@gmail.com</u>

Website: https://jying97.github.io/my_portfolio/

Address: Batu Kawan, Penang, Malaysia.

About / Summary

As an experienced test process and equipment engineer, I specialize in validating, implementing, controlling, and optimizing test process framework to ensure the reliability and performance of complex system. Besides that, I also have expertise in data analytic and coding.

Strengths

- Six sigma lean manufacturing
- Problem solving / Troubleshooting
- Data analysis & visualization
- Coding & automation

Work History

INTEL TECHNOLOGY SDN. BHD [06/2020 to Current] @ Kulim, Kedah

Grade 6 - Module Engineer [Year 2024 - Now]

- Improvement project: Qualified test program to enable a feature which can save ~47% TTR on fail events.
- Lean manufacturing project: Modifying & standardized config for PCO which saved ~0.31hrs of conversion time.
- Outsource: Delivered training & provided investigation finding during Factory cert activities.
- Unit exit: WIP clearing activities, cycle count & tool inventory compilation for space & budget preparation. Disposition & hands-on tools deinstallation for resale & reuse.
- Audit backend team: Documents data mapping & retrieving for custom audit.

Grade 5 - Test Process and Equipment Engineer [Year 2022 - 2024]

- Improvement project: Experiment & deployed continuous testing process to eliminate ~40% of capacity wastage.
- Automation project: Developed python script to auto summarize data which saved ~80% of data preparation work for RMA.
- Quality: Detected & recovered quality issue in house & prevented escapee to customer.
- Product transfer project / New product integration (NPI): Obtained NPI Factory cert & Transfer cert.
- Lean manufacturing project: Implemented lean process on part replacement process, helps in manufacturing efficiency saved ~\$4.9k/year.
- Machine learning project: Assisted validate & provide data samples to re-train text bucket machine learning model to improve the accuracy.
- Defect reduction project: Coordinate & plan new part DOE, validation, implementation & monitoring which success resulted in < 1% fallout.
- Excursion management: Lead & drive xRB with 8D.

Grade 3 - Test Process and Equipment Engineer [Year 2020 - 2022]

- Cost saving / rework reduction project: Analysed data with pareto technique and deployed new test that saved ~60% of an expensive component which costs ~USD\$2.7K per unit.
- Customer first attitude: Performed new part DOE & qual plan to fix customer issue.
- Quality control: Deployed daily monitoring script to ensure the quality and process of the new part installation done correctly by manufacturing.
- Yield improvement project / Machine learning project: Analysing, training and modelling data for a predictive machine learning model with an accuracy of 90% and improve system first pass yield by 20%.
- Interactive reporting system: Developed PowerBI dashboard and improved engineering data reporting TPT by 50%.
- Process control system (PCS): Developed script using SQLpathfinder for auto trigger daily reporting, monitoring and abnormality detection.
- Responsible: Expanded scope to take up responsibility on more products.
- Leadership: Lead & prevented line down of a product by implemented new test program immediately within a week.
- Excursion management: Lead & drive xRB with 8D.

TOP GLOVE SDN. BHD. [Oct 2018 - Dec 2018] @ Klang, Selangor.

Trainee (Industrial training / Internship)

 Project management, power distribution and protection design, vendor communication, site visits.

Technical Software Tools

- Microsoft 365 Applications (eg: Excel, Word, PowerPoint & etc)
- Generative AI (eg: ChatGPT, Copilot & etc)
- Visual Studio Code / Visual Studio
- Spyder & Jupyter Notebook
- JMP
- Power BI
- GitHub
- MATLAB
- MPLAB
- CICON PLC
- Electronic Design Automation (EDA)
- Bambu Lab
- Free CAD

Operating System

Window, MacOS, Ubuntu (Linux)

Programming languages

Python, C / C++, CMD, Jsl script, SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Technical Hardware Tools

- Oscilloscope
- Multimeter
- Frequency counter
- Power supply (bench type)
- Torque screwdrivers & allen keys
- Soldering station
- Microscope / Magnifier

Certificates

- Six Sigma Yellow Belt (AIGPE™)
- Advanced Python Scripting. (PSDC)Power supply (bench type)
- Data Scientist Basic, Intermediate & Advanced. (PSDC)
- Microsoft Excel Intermediate to Advanced. (PSDC)
- Machine Learning A-Z: Al, Python & R. (Udemy)
- The Complete SQL Bootcamp: Go from Zero to Hero. (Udemy)
- Business Writing Skills for Operation Professional. (Speakright Consultancy)
- Presenting to Influence. (Speakright Consultancy)
- The Essentials of Finance and Accounting for Executives. (PSDC)
- ATM Data Fluency Level 3: Advanced (Intel)

Education

- ❖ B. Eng. (Hons) Electrical & Electronic [Year 2016 Year 2020]
 - UTAR (Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman)
 - CPGA: 3.69 (First Class)
 - USSDC (soft skill): Merit
- Foundation in Science [Year 2015 Year 2016]
 - UTAR (Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman)
 - CPGA: 3.68
- PLKN (National service training programme) [Year 2015]
 - Member of marching drill formation.
- SPM [Year 2013 Year 2014]
 - SMK Gurun
 - 8A, 2B

Reference

Goh Fong Hsia

- Intel / Module Engineering Manager
- Phone: +6012-4320859
- Email: fong.hsia.goh@intel.com

Teoh Hooi Choon

- Intel / Module Engineering Manager
- Phone: +6012-7004986
- Email: hooi.choon.teoh@intel.com